Okay, so let's talk about relationships
then.
In this case, we're talking activity
relationships, right?
Relationship between one activity and
another.
Now, remember the methodology that we're
covering, our methodology that PMI tests
you regarding schedule is critical path
method.
And critical path method is part of the
PDM, or the precedence diagramming method,
also known as AON, activity or node.
So you could see either of those terms.
You could see CPM, which
is critical path method, PDM,
precedence diagramming
method, A-O-N, activity on note.
And the PDM, precedence
diagramming method, uses
the critical path method
to develop the schedule.
And there are four
PDM relationships, right,
which we're going to
cover in just a second.
However, there's a couple of important
terms, though, that you need to know,
that you need to be aware of, and these
terms here, predecessors and successor.
So a predecessor basically
means it comes before an
activity, and a successor
means it comes after an activity.
So you've got two activities, A and B,
right?
So A is a predecessor of B and B is a
successor of A.
And the general convention, whenever you
see a box like this, right, on the
left-hand side is the start of the activity,
on the right-hand side of the finish.
So we're always going from left to right.
okay so let's talk about the uh the four
types of relationships right so you have a
finish to start a start to start on the
next slide a finish to finish and a start
to finish these are the four relationship
so let's talk about each of these uh in
turn so a finish to start relationship so
finish to start as the name suggests you
have to finish one activity before you can
start the next activity right so a finish
to start is always you
finish to start is always you
finish one activity before
you start the next activity.
And this is the most common type of
relationship.
This is the most common type.
We always want to try and finish one
activity before we start another activity.
So the very simple example here,
when you're building a house, right?
You need to finish the foundations.
We need to dig the foundations before we
can start putting up the walls.
You don't start, you don't put up the
walls first, and then, I mean,
you don't frame the house first and then
dig the foundations.
No, you have to dig the foundations first,
and then you can start frame.
So it has a finished start relationship.
You have to finish one activity before you
can start the next.
Then you have a start to start
relationship.
And in a start to start
then, basically saying one
activity has to start before
another activity can start.
So an example here, let's see
you've got an author writing a
book and you have an editor
that's going to review the book.
Now the author doesn't
necessarily need to finish
writing the book before
the editor starts reviewing.
The author can start writing the book.
They can write the first chapter,
for example.
While they're writing
the second chapter, the
editor can start
reviewing the first chapter.
So that is a start-to-start relationship.
One activity has to start before the other
activity can start.
Now, be very careful here.
Because some organisations or some
methodologies, a start to start can
sometimes mean both activities start at
the same time.
Not for PDM and therefore not for the PMP
exam.
A start to start specifically
means one activity
has to start before the
other activity can start.
Okay.
Now another relationship is this one here.
a finish-to-finish relationship.
One activity has to finish before the
other activity can finish.
Again, not both finish at the same time.
For PDM, one activity has to finish before
the other activity can finish.
So, in our kitchen remodeling example,
right, remember the work breakdown
structure example, where we have the
kitchen remodeling.
Well, one of those tasks that
we need to perform, One of
the work that we need to
perform might be say rewiring.
We need to rewire our kitchen.
Well, we're rewiring our kitchen and we're
installing new appliances.
Well, the rewiring
activity has to finish before
the appliance installation
activity can finish.
They can both be run in parallel,
but one has to finish before the other.
So as we're rewiring our kitchen,
as we're installing the electrical system,
we can order our appliances, well,
we can select our appliances, we can order
them, we can have them
delivered, but we can't physically
plug them in if there's
no electrical system there.
So the electrical rewiring has to finish
before the appliance
installation can finish.
So one has to finish before the other.
Another relationship then is this start to
finish relationship, why one activity has
to start before the other activity can
finish.
Now, that's not very common.
You don't often see that.
So that's, I wouldn't say it's rare,
but it's not very common either.
So one very simple example here.
Let's say you're doing a bathroom
remodeling.
And as part of your bathroom remodeling,
you're installing a dry
wall and a doorway.
And you're also going to be installing
this bathtub.
It's a bathroom.
So you can install a bathtub.
And this bathtub is so big, it's not going
to fit through the doorway.
Once the doorway is built,
that bathtub is not going to
get into, we're not going
to fit it into the bathroom.
So we need to get that bathtub into the
bathroom.
So we need to start the
bathtub installation before
we finish the dry wall
and doorway installation.
So that would be a very simple example
then of a start-to-finish relationship.
We need to start the
bathtub installation before
we finish the dry wall
doorway installation.
Another simple example of the start to
finish is think of shift work.
New shift has to start before the old
shift can finish.
The new shift has to start before the old
It's not the all-shift finisher then the
new shift starts.
No, while the old shift is still working,
the new shift has to start.
Once a new shift is started, now the old
shift can finish.
So that would be another example then of a
start-to-finish relationship.
So these are the four
relationships that you
need to know, that
you need to be aware of.
So you have a finish to start,
start to start, finish to finish,
and a start-to-finish.